<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>B3d on Afrikaniz3D Blogfolio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/b3d/</link>
    <description>Recent content in B3d on Afrikaniz3D Blogfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/b3d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FOTJ [Found on the Job]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/portfolio/fotj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/portfolio/fotj/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;![][1]&#xA; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project came about during session working on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/portfolio/retopologizing-m4/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; retopo commission. There were many instances where I&amp;rsquo;d be zoomed-in working on a particular section for some time that started looking like the beginnings of other objects - like hallways, or a funky mechanical part.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I sat on the idea for a while till I could find the &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; polygons to build from..&#xA; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;850&#34; height=&#34;478&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jm6hVHmL-LQ?si=5OLZmfnFrsRBnvQ0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&amp;nbsp;  &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was working on the &lt;strong&gt;flywheel housing&lt;/strong&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLryiPmQj99uABWE4-p4GGluo2kxhR5KWT&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MDP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and selected a circular section with some stray polys. At the time I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sold on the final result, but I knew it was another case of &amp;ldquo;give it time&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Out of Time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/out-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/out-of-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/img/post/P11/p11001.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A while ago I learned about something called the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://learningloop.io/plays/psychology/zeigarnik-effect#:~:text=The%20Zeigarnik%20Effect%20is%20a,dissonance%2C%20which%20improves%20recall%20ability.&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zeigarnik Effect&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;, named after it&amp;rsquo;s creator Bluma Zeigarnik. I discovered it in the form of one of those inspirational-style posters while scrolling on Pinterest, and it came at a time where I was dealing some kind(s) of &lt;em&gt;stuckness&lt;/em&gt; because of how much I resonated with the idea. I&amp;rsquo;d found a word to relate to the feeling. I like to think about it as a kind of blockage comprised of everything set in motion, or tripping over boxes I&amp;rsquo;ve placed &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll deal with it later&amp;rdquo; invisibility cloaks to visually &amp;ldquo;declutter&amp;rdquo; a space. Out of sight, out of mind - but they&amp;rsquo;re still in the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Survey Terminal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/portfolio/chocolate-survey-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/portfolio/chocolate-survey-terminal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/img/portfolio/W8/w8001.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/img/portfolio/W8/w8009.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This EDA was inspired by a &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tidy Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; dataset that looked at the ratings of different cacao been suppliers in different countries. Rather than following the original data challenge, I decided to instead focus on the elements that dealt with South Africa (SA) because my first real look at the data showed that SA had received the lowest ratings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hypothetical challenge I set for myself was to use the data to identify what led to the poor ratings as well as what changes would need to be made to improve future results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Been Busy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/been-busy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/been-busy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/img/post/P9/p9001.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;from me&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/img/post/P9/p9003.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sensor21 banner&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I got to learn my modest way around geometry nodes while developing &lt;a href=&#34;https://blendermarket.com/products/hexes-mini-pack-04&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HEXES Mini Pack 04: Electronic Devices&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I started work on it in January and was having trouble deciding how many to produce and the style to make them in. Using geonodes made it feel more flexible and user-friendly. The first project was &lt;a href=&#34;https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/portfolio/sensor-21/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sensor 21&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, based on an air quality dataset I explored for a portfolio project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;850&#34; height=&#34;478&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6n1L3U4HRUg?si=f1-FdQtEHBbhQl5Q&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&amp;nbsp;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I made the  above walkthrough video to show my process for the antenna. Used Kdentlive for the first time and there are things about it I made the switch from Da Vinci Resolve easier - the interface is simpler, and some features are easier to access.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>M4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/portfolio/retopologizing-m4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/portfolio/retopologizing-m4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a client project I got some time back. The relationship with the client was a strange once, and it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to comment further as I think the whole experience itself was something else. I was no angel myself, but what I took away from it was a lot more than a new monitor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/img/portfolio/W13/w13001.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first piece - the receiver - was easily the hardest. The big mistakes were:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Still</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/still/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/still/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/img/post/P8/p8001.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;from me&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Might just be the combination of things I&amp;rsquo;ve been focusing on lately, but finding a good fit is shifting more and more. So much changes in a month that the draft 2 weeks is so different to the draft of the night before. Found a way to make the data explorations more interesting while also getting to make new stuff as well as following through with older ideas. Nothing goes to waste. This will also let me get more content on &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/rings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/rings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/img/post/P7/p7001.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;from me&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Things are relatively quiet. Regular exercise and mindful eating. The Printer Challenge is still going along with the data exploration exercises. Happy with how the portfolio is shaping up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This website is an example of something I look forward to looking back on in months (and years) to come and be able so see how it slowly solidified - like examining the rings of a tree trunk with the passage of time (after you chop it down&amp;hellip;?&amp;hellip;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What a Finish</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-12-30-what-a-finish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-12-30-what-a-finish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/img/post/P6/p6001.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;from me&#34;&gt;&#xA;The past few days really drove home how much of a break I need. That coupled with the growing pains of using Linux was what really shifted the last two months by a few gears. It did, though, have surprising benefits.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Started a &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prusa Printer Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; for myself in 2023&amp;raquo; as a way of turning free content into a new tool for the business. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/contest&#34;&gt;contests&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/&#34;&gt;Printables&lt;/a&gt; are fun incentives to create - and be creative.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nutvember 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-11-28-nutvember-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-11-28-nutvember-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/img/post/P5/p5001.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;from me&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A year ago I created the Nutvember kitbashing set of nuts and bolts to&amp;hellip; celebrate(?) No Nut November (NNN). Also known as &lt;a href=&#34;https://movember.com&#34;&gt;Movember&lt;/a&gt; it was something I&amp;rsquo;d been casually familiar with and I wanted to change that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read some papers, some very old and others recent. Masturbation is what I read the most on because I wanted to find conversations on the act that weren&amp;rsquo;t focused on the psycho-sexual parts explored by the Freuds or the Kinseys. It ultimately came down to education, conventional and/or specifically sex.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letting Go?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-10-31-letting-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-10-31-letting-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/img/post/P4/p4001.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;from me&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These blog posts started out with the purpose of covering what I thought were things worth sharing and, in a sense, backing-up some experiences to revisit. The episode where Terry (Brooklyn Nine-Nine) resolves to leave the force, but is persuaded otherwise by Holt. Later episodes made a theme of it and it re-framed the relationship dynamics for me. When I look back I see a lot of it in my own life on both sides and it&amp;rsquo;s given me a lot of pause recently, making some obvious decisions/commitments difficult.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BRAUBERRY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/portfolio/brauberry-brand-mashup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/portfolio/brauberry-brand-mashup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Brand Mash-Up series was one of the first bigger projects on my YouTube channel that I started as a means of both expanding on what I had been doing as well as learning new tools such as Blender. The idea for &lt;strong&gt;BRAUBERRY&lt;/strong&gt; was a response to the need for being careful when handling intellectual properties I didn&amp;rsquo;t own in the case they might endanger my YouTube channel. It was also a fun opportunity to see what could come about from merging two seemingly non-related brands.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Site Loading</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-07-17-new-site-loading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-07-17-new-site-loading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;getting-the-ball-rolling&#34;&gt;Getting the Ball Rolling&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the things I got out of completing the Data Analytics certification was being introduced to R and RStudio. I&amp;rsquo;ve since learned how to build a site using RStudio. This is the result so far and I&amp;rsquo;m currently filling it out daily till I get it to a level of completeness that covers what I can display.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-learning-process&#34;&gt;The Learning Process&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Early on I was fortunate enough to find &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCA-hX4v0FEIKOzY8yikt8ow&#34;&gt;CradleToGraveR&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; channel on YouTube where he does an amazing job at walking you through the steps and also showing you other routes in case you run into some trouble - which I did on many occasions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roundhouse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/portfolio/roundhouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/portfolio/roundhouse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;![Running Project Header Image][1]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I stumbled upon a video discussing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RoGuvvzHY1A&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Earth-Integrated&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; homes. Built using reinforced ferrous-concrete, and then covered with a layer of earth. A striking feature was the visual quality of the interior spaces which were domical in shape and capped with a skylight. The quality of the space is something I wanted to carry through in this project along with some personal touches.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;![Moodboard][2]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The moodboard above covers most of the aspects that can be found in the minimal-rustic-camping umbrella. The shelter is designed for short-term residents, travelers, or generally&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
