<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design on Afrikaniz3D Blogfolio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Design on Afrikaniz3D Blogfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BRAUBERRY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/portfolio/brauberry-brand-mashup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/portfolio/brauberry-brand-mashup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Brand Mash-Up series was one of the first bigger projects on my YouTube channel that I started as a means of both expanding on what I had been doing as well as learning new tools such as Blender. The idea for &lt;strong&gt;BRAUBERRY&lt;/strong&gt; was a response to the need for being careful when handling intellectual properties I didn&amp;rsquo;t own in the case they might endanger my YouTube channel. It was also a fun opportunity to see what could come about from merging two seemingly non-related brands.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HEXES Mini Pack Series</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/portfolio/hexes-mini-pack-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/portfolio/hexes-mini-pack-series/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Forming a clear picture of the path to take towards a goal, something I am relearning, is affected by a variety of things, chief of which being that I find it difficult to push through a contrived/inauthentic path. Testing authenticity, I&amp;rsquo;m sure, has universally championed rubrics I&amp;rsquo;ll undoubtedly discover ahead now that the idea has been “committed to the bits.” How this ties to this project are the motivations that punctuated its creation. Rather than explaining things that can be gathered from careful observation, I&amp;rsquo;ve instead chosen to discuss the bits unrecorded, the unseen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roundhouse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/portfolio/roundhouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/portfolio/roundhouse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;![Running Project Header Image][1]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I stumbled upon a video discussing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RoGuvvzHY1A&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Earth-Integrated&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; homes. Built using reinforced ferrous-concrete, and then covered with a layer of earth. A striking feature was the visual quality of the interior spaces which were domical in shape and capped with a skylight. The quality of the space is something I wanted to carry through in this project along with some personal touches.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;![Moodboard][2]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The moodboard above covers most of the aspects that can be found in the minimal-rustic-camping umbrella. The shelter is designed for short-term residents, travelers, or generally&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
