<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Afrikaniz3D Blogfolio</title>
    <link>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Afrikaniz3D Blogfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BRAUBERRY [Brand Mash-Up Project]</title>
      <link>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/portfolio/brauberry-brand-mash-up-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 20:44:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/portfolio/brauberry-brand-mash-up-project/</guid>
      <description>The Brand Mash-Up series was one of the first bigger projects on my YouTube channel that I started as a means of both expanding on what I had been doing as well as learning new tools such as Blender. The idea for BRAUBERRY was a response to the need for being careful when handling intellectual properties I didn&amp;rsquo;t own in the case they might endanger my YouTube channel. It was also a fun opportunity to see what could come about from merging two seemingly non-related brands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HEXES Mini Pack Series</title>
      <link>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/portfolio/hexes-mini-pack-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 13:51:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/portfolio/hexes-mini-pack-series/</guid>
      <description>Forming a clear picture of the path to take towards a goal, something I am relearning, is affected by a variety of things, chief of which being that I find it difficult to push through a contrived/inauthentic path. Testing authenticity, I&amp;rsquo;m sure, has universally championed rubrics I&amp;rsquo;ll undoubtedly discover ahead now that the idea has been “committed to the bits.” How this ties to this project are the motivations that punctuated its creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Printing</title>
      <link>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/portfolio/3d-printing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 10:43:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/portfolio/3d-printing/</guid>
      <description>#3
Stuck to regular modeling for this set moving forward mostly for the cleaner wireframes, but also to make it easier for anyone to edit the file before printing.
#2
Second entry in the 3d printing exploration looked at workflows for creating the models. Normally would have gone with regular boolean and subdivision, but wanted to try find a quicker option. This ended up being going from blocking-out with booleans and then using the remesh modifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Explorations using R Studio</title>
      <link>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/portfolio/data-explorations-using-r-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 13:14:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/portfolio/data-explorations-using-r-studio/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this data exploration is to apply and the practice the skills gained from the Google Data Analytics Professional Certification. The data being explored relates to South African energy, primarily electricity. This exercise will be replicated on other tools later on such as Power BI and SQL.
The datasets are mostly in .csv format and were collected from the following sources:
Eskom
World Bank
Energy Data
Regulatory Indicator for Sustainable Energy (RISE)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drone Cinematography</title>
      <link>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/portfolio/drone-cinematography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 12:57:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/portfolio/drone-cinematography/</guid>
      <description>2019 marked the first full year of AFRIKANIZ3D. I was still mostly working on architectural projects. I bought a drone, the first generation DJI Mini. The timing of the COVID-19 pandemic delayed things &amp;ldquo;a bit&amp;rdquo; through various restrictions, but I&amp;rsquo;m happy that this gets to be part of the mix and look forward to seriously playing with it again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power BI Dashboards</title>
      <link>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/portfolio/work10-power-bi-dashboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/portfolio/work10-power-bi-dashboards/</guid>
      <description>This entry is related to South African energy exploration that on RStudio that you can look at here. My intentions for this segment of the exploration is to take the same data and generate some dashboards that you would find for up-to-date looks on some statistics - snapshots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a Finish</title>
      <link>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/post/2022-12-30-what-a-finish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/post/2022-12-30-what-a-finish/</guid>
      <description>from me
The past few days really drove home how much of a break I need. That coupled with the growing pains of using Linux was what really shifted the last two months by a few gears. It did, though, have surprising benefits.
Started a “Prusa Printer Challenge” for myself in 2023&amp;gt;&amp;gt; as a way of turning free content into a new tool for the business. The contests on Printables are fun incentives to create - and be creative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nutvember 2022</title>
      <link>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/post/2022-11-28-nutvember-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/post/2022-11-28-nutvember-2022/</guid>
      <description>A year ago I created the Nutvember kitbashing set of nuts and bolts to&amp;hellip; celebrate(?) No Nut November (NNN). Also known as Movember it was something I&amp;rsquo;d been casually familiar with and I wanted to change that.
Read some papers, some very old and others recent. Masturbation is what I read the most on because I wanted to find conversations on the act that weren&amp;rsquo;t focused on the psycho-sexual parts explored by the Freuds or the Kinseys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letting Go?</title>
      <link>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/post/2022-10-31-letting-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/post/2022-10-31-letting-go/</guid>
      <description>These blog posts started out with the purpose of covering what I thought were things worth sharing and, in a sense, backing-up some experiences to revisit. The episode where Terry (Brooklyn Nine-Nine) resolves to leave the force, but is persuaded otherwise by Holt. Later episodes made a theme of it and it re-framed the relationship dynamics for me. When I look back I see a lot of it in my own life on both sides and it&amp;rsquo;s given me a lot of pause recently, making some obvious decisions/commitments difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vibes</title>
      <link>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/post/vibes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/post/vibes/</guid>
      <description>There was a theme and set of topics set for this month that had to be scrapped,
so this post will touch on some other stuff to keep the monthly train going - and hopefully let off some real steam on the outside.
Got back into reading for the habit more than the learning. I try to do it first thing everyday while it&amp;rsquo;s still dark. It sets such a good tone for the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog of Changes</title>
      <link>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/post/2022-08-22-blog-of-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/post/2022-08-22-blog-of-changes/</guid>
      <description>Burnout isn’t the only reason I stopped making artwork for a while. I also realised I’d been, for the longest time, guilty of only doing works that would be seen. Practice was meaningless if it would only be seen by me, if it wouldn’t eventually be sent out to get hearts and likes. Sad, but mostly true. It’s a weird thing to tackle, but the thing that helped me the most was to commit to daily routines of producing/exploring with the intent of doing the same thing better over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Site Loading</title>
      <link>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/post/2022-07-17-new-site-loading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afrikaniz3d.netlify.app/post/2022-07-17-new-site-loading/</guid>
      <description>Getting the Ball RollingOne of the things I got out of completing the Data Analytics certification was being introduced to R and RStudio. I’ve since learned how to build a site using RStudio. This is the result so far and I’m currently filling it out daily till I get it to a level of completeness that covers what I can display.
The Learning ProcessEarly on I was fortunate enough to find CradleToGraveR’s channel on YouTube where he does an amazing job at walking you through the steps and also showing you other routes in case you run into some trouble - which I did on many occasions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
